Now we're going to talk about how to do inference on Bayes Net.
现在我们要讨论如何根据贝叶斯网络进行推理
We'll start with our familiar network.
我们首先从熟悉的网络开始
And we'll talk about a method called enumeration.
要讨论的方法称为列举法
Which goes through all the possibilities, adds them up.
即列出所有可能性 然后相加
And comes up with an answer.
得出一个答案
So what we do is start by stating the problem.
所以我们首先要陈述问题
We're going to ask the question of, what is the probability that the burglar
我们要提出问题 约翰和玛丽都电话的情况下
alarm occurred giving that John called and Mary called.
发生盗窃案的概率 即 P(+b|+j,+m)
We'll use the definition conditional probability to answer this.
我们使用条件概率的定义进行解答
So this query is equal to the joint probability distribution of all three
那么这个查询变量等于所有三个变量的联合概率分布 P(+b,+j,+m)
variables divided by the conditonalized variables.
除以条件化变量 P(+j,+m)
Now note I'm using a notation here,
注意我这里使用的符号表示法
where instead of writing out probability of some variable equals true.
没有写出一些变量的概率为真
I'm just using the notation plus and then the variable name in lowercase.
而是使用符号 + 然后是变量名称的小写形式
And if I wanted the negation, I would use negation sign.
如果要否定 我使用符号 ﹁
Notice there's a different notation
注意还有一种不同的符号表示法
where instead of writing out the plus and negation signs.
没有使用正负号
We just use the variable name itself.
我们只使用变量名称
P(e) to indicate E is true.
P(e) 表示 E 为真
That notation works well but
这种符号表示法非常有效
it can get confusing between does P(e) mean E is true.
但是容易产生困惑 P(e) 是否表示 E 为真
Or does it mean e is a variable?
还是表示 e 是一个变量呢？
And so we're going to to stick to the notation where we explicitly have
那我们还是继续使用清晰明确的
the pluses and negation signs.
+ 和 ﹁ 符号表示法
To do inference by enumeration, you first take a conditional probability and
通过列举法进行推理 你首先得到一个条件概率
rewrite it as unconditional probabilities.
并重新写为无条件概率
Now we enumerate all the atomic probabilities and
现在我们列举所有原子概率
calculate the sum of products.
计算乘积之和
Let's look at just the complex term on the numerator first.
我们首先来看分子中的复杂项
The procedure for
计算分母的程序
figuring out the denominator will be similar and we'll skip that.
也是类似的 我们就跳过不讲了
The probability of these three terms together
这三项的概率可以通过
can be determined by enumerating all possible values of the hidden variables.
列举隐变量的所有可能值来确定
In this case there are two, E and A, so we'll sum over those variables for
在这个例子中有两个隐变量 E 和 A 所以我们把 E 和 A 的
all values of E and for all values of A.
所有值加起来
In this case they're Boolean, so there's only two values of each.
在这个例子中它们都是布尔变量 所以每个变量只有两个值
We ask what's the probability of this unconditional term?
我们会问这个无条件项的概率是多少？
And that we get by summing out over all possibilities, E and A being true or
我们通过汇总所有可能性
false.
即 E 和 A 为真或假 得到结果
Now, to get the values of these atomic events,
现在为了得到这些原子事件的值
we'll have to rewrite this equation in a form that corresponds to
我们重新编写这个等式
the conditional probability tables that we have associated with the Bayes Net.
使它的形式等同于我们在贝叶斯网络相关的条件概率表格
So we'll take this whole expression and rewrite it.
我们得到整个表达式 然后重新编写
It's still a sum over the hidden variables E and A, but now we'll rewrite
这仍然是对隐变量 E 和 A 的求和 但是现在我们
this expression in terms of the parents of each of the nodes in the network.
根据网络中每个节点的双亲 重新编写表达式
So that gives us the product of these five terms,
那么得到这五项的乘积
which we then have to sum over all values of e and a.
然后我们把 e 和 a 的所有值加起来
If we call this product f(e,a), then the whole answer
如果我们把这个乘积叫做 f(e,a) 那么整个答案
is the sum of f for all values of e and a.
是 f 对 e 和 a 所有值的求和
So it's a sum of four terms where each of the terms is a product
所以它是四项的总和 其中每一项都是
of five numbers.
五个数字的乘积
Where do we get the numbers to fill in this equation?
那么我们从哪里获取数字 代入这个等式呢？
&gt;From the conditional probability tables from our model.
从我们模型中的条件概率表格中获取
So let's put the equation back up and we'll ask you for
我们再次看这个等式 然后提问
the case where both e and A, are positive,
e 和 a 都为正的情况
to look up in the conditional probability tables.
观察条件概率表格
And fill in the numbers, for each of these five terms and
填入所有这五项的数字
then multiply them together, and fill in the product
然后相乘 填入乘积